<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:35:59.493" Score="25" ViewCount="1645" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to &quot;pump&quot; a powder the same way liquids can be pumped?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If so, what are the challenges? If not, what are some alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="148" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T08:28:32.950" LastActivityDate="2016-06-28T09:12:52.693" Title="Is it possible to &quot;pump&quot; a powder?" Tags="&lt;pumps&gt;&lt;liquid&gt;&lt;fluid-mechanics&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:00.530" Score="22" Body="&lt;p&gt;I believe it's termed &quot;injecting&quot; not &quot;pumping&quot; but yes, it's certainly possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coal fired electric power plants grind the coal to a very fine dust and then blow the dust into the central burner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netl.doe.gov/File%20Library/Research/Coal/major%20demonstrations/cctdp/Round3/bethstl.pdf&quot;&gt;This particular article&lt;/a&gt; is a summary of some DOE research for a Blast Furnace Granulated Coal Injection System Demonstration Project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nfpa.org/~/media/Files/Research/Research%20Foundation/foundation%20proceedings/david_snell.pdf&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; discusses some of the hazards from a National Fire Protection Association perspective.  Coal dust having the particular dangerous property of being explosive and all that...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as specifics regarding danger, I suspect it will vary depending upon the material(s) involved in the powder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T18:41:00.530" CommentCount="5" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:20.310" Score="8" ViewCount="281" Body="&lt;p&gt;What would be the best type of steel to specify? Would a heavy galvanization suffice?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there specialty paints/coatings available for this particular application? If so, how long do they last?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditDate="2015-10-18T18:40:48.110" LastActivityDate="2015-10-18T18:40:48.110" Title="What kind of protection should I give structural steel in a natatorium (swiming pool) environment?" Tags="&lt;steel&gt;&lt;structures&gt;&lt;corrosion&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="248" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:51.527" Score="4" ViewCount="90" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think, actually the first row is needed is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barometric_formula&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;barometric height formula&lt;/a&gt; for the mix of gases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main problem I can see, the curves describing the minimal energy (kinetic + gravitational/centrifugal) won't be any more a simple derivative, but a functional equation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think, this or similar equations could be useful in very separate areas (isotope separation, estimating high atmosphere components of planets, etc.) Despite I couldn't find anything with google about this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, the question is: we have a high gas mixture in constant g gravity and T temperature. We known the p1, p2, ... partial pressures of the gases on the h=0. Of course we know every relevant constants of the gases, too. What is their minimal-energy, isothermic, height-dependent partial pressure function pn(h)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="160" LastEditDate="2015-02-14T15:04:27.127" LastActivityDate="2015-02-14T15:04:27.127" Title="Multi-gas barometric height formula in isotope separation devices?" Tags="&lt;pressure&gt;&lt;gas&gt;&lt;nuclear-technology&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="8" CreationDate="2015-01-20T19:49:53.683" Score="9" ViewCount="226" Body="&lt;p&gt;The United States have different rules about exactly how one obtains an engineering license, but the general process is the FE exam, a few years of work, and the PE exam. Suppose one then wishes to practice engineering in Germany. What are the legal requirements for doing so?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" Title="What is the process of transferring an engineering license from the United States to Germany?" Tags="&lt;licensure&gt;&lt;international&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2015-01-20T20:27:48.367" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;Unlike within the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_and_licensure_in_engineering&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;United States and the PE license&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn't appear that it's possible to receive an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_Engineer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EUR ING&lt;/a&gt; license by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nspe.org/resources/licensure/resources/licensure-comity&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;direct comity&lt;/a&gt;.  EU Engineering licensing is handled by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FEANI&lt;/a&gt;, and on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?id=261&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EUR ING&lt;/a&gt; page they state: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Application is open only to individuals if they are members of an engineering association represented in FEANI through a National Member&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it may be possible to join one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?id=57&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;German FEANI members&lt;/a&gt; and see if they can support a reciprocity or comity process.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;There are other member organization in other countries, but your question specifically mentioned Germany.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digging a bit deeper, it does appear that there may be limited cases where an EUR ING will be awarded based upon sufficient experience as a professional engineer.  Take a look through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?eID=tx_nawsecuredl&amp;amp;u=0&amp;amp;file=fileadmin/PDF_Documents/EUR_ING_Tittle/Guide_to_the_Register_FINAL_approved_GA_2013.pdf&amp;amp;t=1421941885&amp;amp;hash=f78dd0dcf1b44b41a9cc45e17cc6500d1f436621&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FEANI EUR ING guide&lt;/a&gt;, in particular Section 5 which details the minimum requirements.  Most of the cases cover qualifications based upon an education received within an FEANI member country.  Section 5.4b deals with special circumstances and provides the potential pathway that you could receive an EUR ING license.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless it is possible to consider such alternative routes. Very strict procedures, however, have then to be followed, (see 7.1), and the applicant must have at least 15 years of Professional Engineering Experience recognized by FEANI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So it does appear to be possible, but again, it's not as simple as the comity process within the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="16" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T20:31:25.093" Score="12" ViewCount="244" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently having an issue where features of my machined parts are warping. I am using Alloy 7050 Type I and Type III in this particular case. Using a feeler gauge and a certified, calibrated granite slab, I am getting out-of-flatness measurements up to .009, which is significantly out of tolerance relative to my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have decided to construct a statistically-designed experiment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_of_experiments#Experimental_designs_after_Fisher&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;design of experiments&lt;/a&gt;) to find which specific factors are playing a role, but I want to ensure that I am including all of the factors which may contribute.  I don't want to lead the conversation too much by posting what I already listed, but I am looking for others' opinions on what might cause this kind of warping/deflection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-04-27T16:25:03.123" LastActivityDate="2016-08-05T22:48:57.023" Title="In aluminum machining, what are the most common factors that might cause a machined component to have warping issues?" Tags="&lt;mechanical-engineering&gt;&lt;machining&gt;&lt;aluminum&gt;&lt;quality-engineering&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T21:19:03.447" Score="3" ViewCount="131" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently considering turning my fascination with magnets into a diy activity. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How feasible is it for a hobbyist to construct a working model of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maglev&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;maglev&lt;/a&gt; device?&#xA;I'm looking to build something  really small for now,just a demonstrative prototype that can hover over a surface.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for a rough idea of cost, time and materials. Is it something that can be attempted while working a full time job?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know of any good starting points in terms of literature? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="42" LastEditorUserId="42" LastEditDate="2015-01-23T12:17:53.730" LastActivityDate="2015-01-23T12:17:53.730" Title="Magnetic levitation" Tags="&lt;electrical-engineering&gt;&lt;linear-motors&gt;&lt;magnets&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="5" FavoriteCount="0" ClosedDate="2015-01-21T23:07:02.393" />
  <row Id="12" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T21:45:26.513" Score="8" ViewCount="125" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am examining a watershed and determining runoff using the RTK method. I basically use a 'guess and check the hydrograph' method right now. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.innovyze.com/products/infoswmm/calibrator.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;I've seen calibrators&lt;/a&gt; that use a mutation and convergence criteria using root mean square but I've had limited success using them. How can I perform this analysis more efficiently than using my 'guess and check' method?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="40" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-02-26T16:43:41.073" LastActivityDate="2015-02-26T16:43:41.073" Title="Determining RTK parameters for runoff analysis" Tags="&lt;hydrology&gt;&lt;water-resources&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="13" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T21:49:29.263" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;You may also look into pneumatic conveying.  It involves &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluidization&quot;&gt;fluidization of the particles&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This simply uses pressure differential to move any bulk material. It's used a lot in industrial applications.  You can read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nol-tec.com/answers-to-eight-common-questions.html&quot;&gt;summary of those systems, here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="40" LastEditorUserId="104" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T02:48:11.267" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T02:48:11.267" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="14" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="142" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:03:47.020" Score="15" ViewCount="779" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think, here is the main problem the difference between the internal and the external temperature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, in Saudi Arabia, in 50 C, a passive house needed probably much sophisticated planning as in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to the traditional cooling systems, in the second case is enough only to get a cooling system with bigger power. I think, they are much more scalable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is it anyways possible?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="46" LastEditDate="2015-01-24T19:49:44.740" LastActivityDate="2016-08-27T09:59:53.630" Title="How are passive houses made in very hot regions (like Saudi Arabia)?" Tags="&lt;civil-engineering&gt;&lt;architecture&gt;&lt;cooling&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="16" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="19" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:16:03.560" Score="6" ViewCount="322" Body="&lt;p&gt;Liquid hydrogen cooling could be some intermediate solution between helium and liquid nitrogen based cooling.  For example, some type of superconductors could be cooled by liquid H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, and this could be much cheaper than the liquid He.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are their most characteristic applications in the industry?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="63" LastEditDate="2015-01-20T22:58:57.157" LastActivityDate="2015-02-03T12:54:06.913" Title="Do liquid hydrogen-based cooling devices exist and what are they used for?" Tags="&lt;superconduction&gt;&lt;cryogenics&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="17" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="16" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:31:40.093" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;Gaseous hydrogen is often used to cool the large generators in power plants. &quot;Hydrogen’s low gas density, high specific heat, and high thermal conductivity&quot; are listed in the GE link as the major drivers behind its use. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydrogen-cooled_turbo_generator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydrogen-cooled_turbo_generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.control.com/thread/1267097548&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.control.com/thread/1267097548&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://powergen.gepower.com/plan-build/products/generators/hydrogen-cooled.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://powergen.gepower.com/plan-build/products/generators/hydrogen-cooled.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the matter of explosions - hydrogen is not particularly explosive without oxygen present. The goal, then, is to provide a system that keeps the hydrogen free from impurities (air) by sealing it off from the outside air. The purity of the hydrogen in the system is constantly monitored, and in an emergency the gas is evacuated by CO2. It's also worth noting that while helium is not explosive and very similar to H2 physically, it is too expensive to use as a cooling medium.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="45" LastEditorUserId="45" LastEditDate="2015-02-03T12:54:06.913" LastActivityDate="2015-02-03T12:54:06.913" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="18" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:34:59.617" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Safety issues in a &quot;natatorium&quot; (swimming pool) environment include the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1) Chlorine and other high acid gases that can corrode the steel. Both galvanization and paints/coatings can help, until the weather wears the protection away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2) Water freezing and thawing. Basically, you need to keep water away from the pool at times when in it is likely to expand or contract through freezing and thawing, so that this doesn't happen. Mostly a problem for northern climes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3) Algae, molds, etc. You need to keep away organic products that will encourage them to grow, and create destructive acids or other compounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastEditorUserId="62" LastEditDate="2015-01-20T23:36:38.757" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T23:36:38.757" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="19" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="16" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:36:55.360" Score="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;The combustion chamber and nozzle of the Space Shuttle main engine were cooled with liquid hydrogen.  Liquid hydrogen was also the fuel.  It was used as a coolant before it was burned (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regenerative_cooling_%28rocket%29&quot;&gt;regenerative cooling&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/bc/Ssme_schematic.svg&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another example is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SABRE_%28rocket_engine%29&quot;&gt;air breathing rocket engine SABRE&lt;/a&gt;.  Here too liquid hydrogen is used as fuel.  It's also used for liquefying the atmospheric oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/PqrXj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the industry, one advantage that liquid helium and nitrogen have over hydrogen is that helium and nitrogen are inert and non-combustible.  Probably less corrosive too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;p.s.&lt;/em&gt; The question has a &lt;a href=&quot;/questions/tagged/superconduction&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged 'superconduction'&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;superconduction&lt;/a&gt; tag.  So, I don't know if this is the sort of application of liquid hydrogen cooling that the O.P. is looking for.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="63" LastEditorUserId="63" LastEditDate="2015-01-31T06:30:22.057" LastActivityDate="2015-01-31T06:30:22.057" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="20" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="91" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:41:57.420" Score="6" ViewCount="169" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm making a robot for the Sparkfun AVC. I was curious if I could use only the knowledge about&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How the car is being steered at every time interval,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many times the wheels have rotated,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to get a general sense of where the car is. I would use computer vision to avoid immediate dangers. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is any slipping causing false counts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="74" LastEditorUserId="16" LastEditDate="2015-01-24T02:45:20.707" LastActivityDate="2015-03-23T23:47:36.393" Title="Knowing how many times the rear wheels have rotated, and the angle of the front wheels at every time interval, how do I find the location of a car?" Tags="&lt;control-engineering&gt;&lt;robotics&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="5" />
  <row Id="21" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:49:09.513" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;You can pump both liquids and powders into a &quot;mold&quot; using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Injection_moulding&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;injection molding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It works more easily with liquids, but it can also be done with small particles such as powders that are injected into heated molds with sufficient force.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T22:49:09.513" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="22" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="83" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:53:44.837" Score="4" ViewCount="960" Body="&lt;p&gt;I recently had a project where I made an aluminum linkage (similar to a scissor lift) operated by linear actuators. Aluminum pieces were fabricated from 6061 &quot;standard&quot; aluminum stock, 6mm (0.25 inch) thick. The bars are at most 750x75mm (30x3&quot;). The application was mostly cosmetic (for a special effect) rather than lifting or exerting much force.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used shoulder bolts with a nylon washer between the aluminum pieces to reduce friction, and standard zinc-plated steel washers on the exterior sides.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem I encountered was tightening the bolt too much would result in too much friction, whereas too loose would result in one of the aluminum pieces coming slightly off the shoulder of the bolt, skewing, and causing similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would be a better way to create a reliable pivot point that doesn't require constant adjustment?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I put together this illustration as an example:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/m1Psy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linkage Description&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="57" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditDate="2015-10-18T18:56:36.563" LastActivityDate="2015-10-18T18:56:36.563" Title="What method can I use to make a pivot point in an aluminum linkage?" Tags="&lt;bolting&gt;&lt;aluminum&gt;&lt;linkage&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="23" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:58:36.060" Score="8" ViewCount="59" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm investigating communition processes at work, and from my studies I know that there are different breakage models for different modes (Compression, attrition, fracture etc). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far I have only seen population models for ball mills in use. These models use time, size fraction and axial distance in the mill to specify the mass fraction of material at any given location in time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am wondering if similar models exist for other communition devices (Gyratory or Jaw crushers) and if so  what do they look like? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="79" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditDate="2015-10-18T19:01:33.453" LastActivityDate="2015-10-18T19:01:33.453" Title="Recommended models for mineral liberation in crushers" Tags="&lt;process-engineering&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="24" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2015-01-20T22:58:46.440" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Most stainless steels contain nickel around 10%. It is combined normally with chrome and molybdenum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main problem, that a natatorium (i.e. swimming pool) is a highly corrosive environment, and most &quot;stainless&quot; steel alloy is a little bit, slowly, corroding here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/ourHW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even aluminium gets a greyish-white surface layer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the case of constructive materials, the situation is a little bit better. First, because they are mostly in the wall, and the concrete around them partially protects them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In case of freely available surfaces, plastic or painting is yet used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T22:58:46.440" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="25" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:07:59.383" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Compared to most other metals, aluminum is a relatively low performance material. It's useful mainly for low speed, low volume, low temperature variation, and &quot;coarse&quot; applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It tends to &quot;warp,&quot; or otherwise break down in high speed, high volume applications requirement &quot;fine&quot; performance from metals such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Injection_moulding&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;injection molding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T23:07:59.383" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="26" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="112" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:14:48.790" Score="8" ViewCount="222" Body="&lt;p&gt;As far I know, the depleted fuel cells are crushed, and solved in nitric acid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is coming after that? This nitric acid should probably contain a very wide spectrum of different salts (practically, all of the elements between 35-65, and yet a lot of transurans, and a lot of uranium (both of 235 ad 238), and plutonium).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To reach an efficient reprocessing, the uranium (or, at least, the actinid elements) should be somehow separated from this solution. But, AFAIK, they have very different chemical properties. How is it possible to separate only the transuranic materials?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T19:34:43.540" Title="How does nuclear fuel reprocessing work?" Tags="&lt;nuclear-technology&gt;&lt;nuclear-reprocessing&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="27" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="22" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:24:03.133" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;A shoulder bolt is a good approach in applications with light loading, but it needs to be specified such that it can be fully tightened while still allowing the necessary clearance for movement without binding. Use shims where needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can reduce some of the play in the joint by having the bolt threaded into one of the aluminum pieces (but still backed up with a nut for strength). In other words, only one of the aluminum bars needs to turn freely on the bolt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="86" LastEditorUserId="86" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T03:32:44.023" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T03:32:44.023" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="28" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:24:34.500" Score="9" ViewCount="196" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am wondering if there is a spring strong enough and light enough to inflate an airtight membrane so that it floats at Standard Temp &amp;amp; Pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an example, a 10cm cylinder would displace just under 1 gram of air, but a cylindrical spring would have to oppose 162kg of atmospheric force in that configuration.  Is there such a thing as a 162kg 10cm cylindric spring that weighs less than 1 gram?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But that's just one spring design.  More generally, what spring designs provide the highest rate/weight ratio?  What are the current practical limits on spring rate vs spring mass, and using what materials?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="77" LastEditorUserId="77" LastEditDate="2015-01-23T14:21:03.330" LastActivityDate="2016-02-04T18:28:19.247" Title="What are the lightest springs?" Tags="&lt;springs&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="13" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="29" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="20" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:35:57.150" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Knowing the diameter of the wheels and the number of times the wheels turn over in a time interval will give both distance travelled and average speed for that time interval.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You would have to have a continual monitoring system which would record time, wheel revolutions and the angle of the wheels used for steering, most likely relative to the central longitudinal axis of the vehicle. You will need to vectorize the steering data and add the vectors to give the position relative to the  vehicle's starting location.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="90" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T23:35:57.150" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="30" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:39:55.953" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;The work history and temperature history of any metal can make a big difference in the final shape after machining. If the material was cold worked (e.g. rolled) there may be significant residual stresses within the material.  When you start selectively removing material, those stresses may cause the part to warp into a new shape. Cast metals and ones that have been given surface treatments can have the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might be able to address the problem by roughing the part to near-final shape and then running a finishing pass to remove that last little bit of material. Otherwise take a look at the specifications of the material. You may need to heat treat the part to relieve those stresses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a problem that can exist with just about any metal, not just Al.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="68" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T23:39:55.953" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="31" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:41:13.397" Score="5" ViewCount="101" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have some height-adjustment nuts screwed onto vertical threads to support my print-bed for a 3D printer. They are domed nuts and the aluminium build-plate sits on top of the domes, three holes in the plate align with the domes to hold the plate in place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can I protect these nuts from vibration loosening without using thread-locker or similar, so that they remain adjustable?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="95" LastActivityDate="2015-07-22T15:24:39.187" Title="How to prevent vibration loosening whilst maintaining adjustability?" Tags="&lt;vibration&gt;&lt;3d-printing&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="32" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="205" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:41:29.103" Score="4" ViewCount="359" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've found myself tapping and threading a lot lately, and doing so with hand taps and dies.  What would be the next step up from using a drill-press to cut holes for tapping, and a lathe for turning parts to diameter for threading?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are options for making this easier and more precise short of a 6-figure screw or CNC machine?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="77" LastActivityDate="2015-01-24T03:27:27.790" Title="What machinery should I invest in for tapping and threading?" Tags="&lt;machining&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="33" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="75" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:46:47.343" Score="9" ViewCount="534" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's true that most bridges are &quot;two directional.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-way_bridge&quot;&gt;three way bridges&lt;/a&gt; are pretty rare, globally. I can understand why there wouldn't be many for rivers, but if bridges are designed based on the lie of the surrounding ground, why wouldn't there be a large number of non-river sites that would support such bridges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, three out of the world's bridges exist in Michigan (and only ten or so elsewhere in the United States). What is it about the land, topography, or other features of Michigan that cause it to have a disproportionate number of the country's and world's three way bridges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastEditorUserId="62" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T21:31:55.910" LastActivityDate="2015-04-03T03:09:40.567" Title="Why are three way bridges rare?" Tags="&lt;structures&gt;&lt;design&gt;&lt;civil-engineering&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="34" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="41" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:50:02.410" Score="10" ViewCount="364" Body="&lt;p&gt;My design uses a round steel bar inserted through a hole in an aluminium component with a tight fit (no movement). The operating environment is dry, 20-40°C.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do I need to worry about galvanic corrosion, and if so how long will this last before starting to corrode? Also, what storage conditions should I avoid that would accelerate the corrosion?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="95" LastActivityDate="2015-01-25T20:46:59.583" Title="Do I need to worry about galvanic corrosion when inserting a steel bar through aluminium?" Tags="&lt;steel&gt;&lt;corrosion&gt;&lt;materials&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="35" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="99" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:51:19.933" Score="9" ViewCount="206" Body="&lt;p&gt;If I have structural or tool steel that has been treated to some standard (ASTM, SAE, ISO -- e.g., for hardness) but I don't know the details of the treatment, is there a &quot;safe&quot; temperature below which I can work the steel without affecting its performance characteristics?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="77" LastEditorUserId="77" LastEditDate="2015-01-22T16:46:52.107" LastActivityDate="2016-04-18T19:49:00.730" Title="At what temperature do I risk altering the structure of steel?" Tags="&lt;steel&gt;&lt;machining&gt;&lt;metallurgy&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="0" />
  <row Id="36" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="20" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:57:21.430" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;The main problem which I can see in your idea, that your system will have a cumulative error. Only calculating this won't be enough, you will have to find alternate solutions, too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In similar (but maybe bigger) scenarios, for example for drones, there is a similar problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solution is using the wheel rotation counters to get a fast, real-time, but buggy input data (which contains the cumulative error as well). In case of flying drones, this data is coming from gyros and accelerometers, your task is much simpler compared to their.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt;, you should get an alternate information source, too! (In case of the drones it is normally the GPS). This can be GPS, or some other thing - there is a wide spectrum of possibilities. Visual image processing? Pre-calibrated ultrasound markers? Marker paintings on the floor?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I suspect correctly the size of your experiment, maybe the last would be most promising to you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="282" LastEditDate="2015-03-23T23:47:36.393" LastActivityDate="2015-03-23T23:47:36.393" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="37" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="53" CreationDate="2015-01-20T23:59:10.837" Score="8" ViewCount="1276" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am starting to use steel in some of my designs, and while trying to learn more about this material and its properties I have realized that there is so much more to it than I thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How does the grading system used for steel work? For instance, what does &quot;Grade 11SMn30&quot; mean, and how does this affect the properties of the material?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answers/comments indicate there are multiple standards, which I did not know, but I've found out that this is an EN grading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="95" LastEditorUserId="120" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T03:01:00.333" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T03:01:00.333" Title="What does the steel grade &quot;11SMn30&quot; mean?" Tags="&lt;steel&gt;&lt;materials&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="38" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1945" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:03:53.533" Score="4" ViewCount="85" Body="&lt;p&gt;The LTE specification specifies SC-FDMA as the encoding scheme for the reverse link (mobile to base station) when the forward link uses OFDMA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the reason for the difference?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-07-21T23:06:14.437" LastActivityDate="2015-07-21T23:06:14.437" Title="Why does the LTE Specification define SC-FDMA as the modulation scheme for the reverse link?" Tags="&lt;lte&gt;&lt;modulation&gt;&lt;telecommunication&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="39" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="10" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:12:55.177" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, maybe the home-sized magnetic levitation could be a narrow area, where superconducting solutions could be cheap. I explain, why.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although room-temperature superconductivity is a dream, room superconductivity is not. :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are soon superconducting materials which can be cooled by liquid air, and they aren't even costly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Liquid air is also relatively cheap. Maybe a liquid air processing machine were costly, but you don't need to buy that. Only to buy the superconducting alloy, and the liquid air (nitrogen). For the first, I tried ebay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, it depends what you want to reach. I once played chess with figures levitated by Meissner-effect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The result could be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/hxFn9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:12:55.177" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="40" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:13:45.360" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Double nutting can be an easy option for this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was about to describe it myself, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boltscience.com/pages/twonuts.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;these folks&lt;/a&gt; do a great job.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This image, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boltscience.com/pages/twonuts.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;from the article&lt;/a&gt;, models the forces that do the job.  Take note of the contact surfaces between the threading of the bolt, in the top vs. bottom nut:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/htgru.gif&quot; alt=&quot;force model for double nutting&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="68" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-07-21T23:26:51.477" LastActivityDate="2015-07-21T23:26:51.477" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="41" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="34" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:29:30.307" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;Very probably, no.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Galvanic corrosion required the existence of a reactive &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; conductive medium, which you don't have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/GraHA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there is some (for example, at least moist air, or similar) best you can do to paint &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; of the metals, if you can.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, if none of the materials would corrode in an environment, galvanic corrosion is a non-issue (in that environment).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:29:30.307" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="42" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="37" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:30:44.500" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;The numbers from 1 to 9 indicate the type of steel. The first 1 is for carbon steel, and the second 1 and the S mean that sulfur has been added to it. The Mn stands for &quot;manganese&quot; and 30 is the amount of carbon in the steel, expressed as a fraction of 1%. It really means, .30% carbon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More information can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SAE_steel_grades&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt; such as this one. The above answer would be responsive assuming that it is an American designation, but a commenter pointed out that it could be an English code, which would mean something different. In any event, it is the responsibility of the questioner to define these things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastEditorUserId="62" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T00:36:46.960" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:36:46.960" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="43" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="26" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:32:02.570" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;You could try &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nuclear_reprocessing&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, but they note that the article may not meet there quality standards, so I'll stay away from there as a source. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://world-nuclear.org/info/Nuclear-Fuel-Cycle/Fuel-Recycling/Processing-of-Used-Nuclear-Fuel/&quot;&gt;World Nuclear Association&lt;/a&gt; seems more credible, anyway. Their page discusses the process. Quoting the section entitled &quot;Reprocessing today – PUREX&quot; (emphasis mine):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;All commercial reprocessing plants use the well-proven hydrometallurgical PUREX (plutonium uranium extraction) process. This involves dissolving the fuel elements in concentrated nitric acid. C&lt;strong&gt;hemical separation of uranium and plutonium is then undertaken by solvent extraction steps (neptunium – which may be used for producing Pu-238 for thermo-electric generators for spacecraft – can also be recovered if required).&lt;/strong&gt; The Pu and U can be returned to the input side of the fuel cycle – the uranium to the conversion plant prior to re-enrichment and the plutonium straight to MOX fuel fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Block of text $\to$ coherent summary: Chemical solvents are used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Further below, the WNA notes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The used fuel is chopped up and dissolved in hot concentrated nitric acid. The first stage separates the uranium and plutonium in the aqueous nitric acid stream from the fission products and minor actinides by a countercurrent solvent extraction process, using tributyl phosphate dissolved in kerosene or dodecane. In a pulsed column uranium and plutonium enter the organic phase while the fission products and other elements remain in the aqueous raffinate. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;In a second pulsed column uranium is separated from plutonium by reduction with excess U4+ added to the aqueous stream. Plutonium is then transferred to the aqueous phase while the mixture of U4+ and U6+ remains in the organic phase. It is then stripped from the organic solvent with dilute nitric acid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The plutonium nitrate is concentrated by evaporation then subject to an oxalate precipitation process followed by calcination to produce PuO2 in powder form. The uranium nitrate is concentrated by evaporation and calcined to produce UO3 in powder form. It is then converted to UO2 product by reduction in hydrogen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compounds of importance: tributyl phosphate, kerosene and dodecane, and aqueous affinate are used as solvents after the nitric acid. Then there is a reaction with $U^{4+}$, and uranium and plutonium are separated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That's the chemical part. I haven't been able to find much information on the specific mechanical methods (i.e. the pure engineering you were looking for). In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://worldwide.espacenet.com/publicationDetails/originalDocument;jsessionid=VagyIBjpGc8AsrFdt8frL6RZ.espacenet_levelx_prod_2?CC=US&amp;amp;NR=2924506A&amp;amp;KC=A&amp;amp;FT=D&amp;amp;ND=&amp;amp;date=19600209&amp;amp;DB=&amp;amp;locale=en_EP&quot;&gt;the original patent&lt;/a&gt; for PUREX does not cover the mechanical processes, leading me to believe that the exact setup can vary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inl.gov/technicalpublications/Documents/4460757.pdf&quot;&gt;This pdf&lt;/a&gt; is somewhat helpful. It says that the input materials are first chopped up. Perforated baskets are then used to separate this machinery from the rest of the solution; a &quot;wheel dissolver&quot; may be used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do have some information, albeit for a non-PUREX method. For aqueous reprocessing (go to page 12), mixer settlers (mixing chambers with settling chambers), columns and centrifuges are the main pieces of equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="106" LastEditorUserId="106" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T01:16:33.523" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T01:16:33.523" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="44" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:33:25.187" Score="8" ViewCount="280" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am working with 1&quot; medium pressure steam mains (45 psig) for a batch process. Time between batches is usually short (to the order of minutes) but depending on the day the delay can be hours, and even longer over weekends or holidays.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We recently installed a full set of orifice (venturi) type steam traps. When we start up, the orifices can't handle the condensate load and the back up condensate is causing water hammer in some sections of the piping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are a little tight on budget but will look to installing additional (non-orifice) traps in the problem portions of the piping.  In the meantime, we are resorting to manually opening/closing the bypass valves to vent the initial condensate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a better way to prevent condensate backup at startup on a batch process when using orifice/venturi steam traps?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="112" LastEditorUserId="110" LastEditDate="2015-02-10T11:45:32.497" LastActivityDate="2015-07-21T08:29:46.633" Title="Preventing condensate backup at startup with orifice (venturi) steam traps on medium pressure batch process mains?" Tags="&lt;mechanical-engineering&gt;&lt;steam&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="45" PostTypeId="5" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:34:49.273" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;LTE, originally name Long Term Evolution, is a wireless telecommunications standard evolved from the 3GPP family (which includes GSM and UMTS).  The official standard called LTE began with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3gpp.org/specifications/releases/72-release-8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Release 8&lt;/a&gt; of the 3GPP specification.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While commonly referred as a 4G technology, 3GPP Releases 8 and 9 do not officially meet the requirements of 4G but the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ITU-R&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ITU&lt;/a&gt;.  It is not until 3GPP Release 10 (Commonly known as LTE Advanced, does it meet the officially meet the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IMT_Advanced&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;4G requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastEditorUserId="54" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T02:48:22.747" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T02:48:22.747" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="46" PostTypeId="4" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:34:49.273" Score="0" Body="Use this tag for questions about the Long Term Evolution (LTE) wireless telecommunications standard." OwnerUserId="54" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-05-06T16:16:38.433" LastActivityDate="2015-05-06T16:16:38.433" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="47" PostTypeId="5" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" Score="0" Body="" OwnerUserId="-1" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="48" PostTypeId="4" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" Score="0" Body="" OwnerUserId="-1" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:39:11.520" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="49" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:46:00.803" Score="4" ViewCount="1196" Body="&lt;p&gt;This is similar to my Physics.SE question &lt;a href=&quot;http://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/155666/microtops-sunphotometer-sun-target-optics&quot;&gt;Microtops sunphotometer sun target optics&lt;/a&gt; - there I was asking about the optics principles (the answer is no good for my understanding, but I have been able to figure it out myself).  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose behind a sunspotter is to show when a device is lined up in direct view of the sun - vital for fields such as sunphotometry etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This question is given that I now understand the optics principles involved (similar to a magnifying glass, but smaller and does not burn when focused) - &lt;strong&gt;what method can be used to make a rudimentary sunspotter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In particular, I am interested in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a suitable material that would be used for the sun target (as per the Microtops picture on the linked page).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the same orientation of the sun target being perpendicular to the incident light.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I am not interested in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;any device how to make a device that allows viewing of things like eclipses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user52" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditorDisplayName="user52" LastEditDate="2015-02-13T23:57:27.167" LastActivityDate="2015-02-13T23:57:27.167" Title="How can I make a rudimentary sunspotter?" Tags="&lt;materials&gt;&lt;optics&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="50" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="96" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:46:44.707" Score="3" ViewCount="739" Body="&lt;p&gt;Recently, both Zigbee and Z-wave tend to be the most commonly used protocol to communicate between Internet of Things (IoT) devices. Most of these IoT devices tend to have a combination of mechanical or optical related transducer or actuator device component coupled with a micro-controller and respective software stack. What are the major differences between Zigbee 3.0 and Z-Wave in relation to communication between IoT devices?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="110" LastEditDate="2016-05-18T09:42:39.153" LastActivityDate="2016-07-21T00:31:00.460" Title="What are the pros and cons of between Zigbee and Z-Wave communication protocols used in IoT device space?" Tags="&lt;electrical-engineering&gt;&lt;telecommunication&gt;&lt;iot&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="51" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="34" CreationDate="2015-01-21T00:51:59.367" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galvanic_corrosion&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; defines galvanic corrosion as: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&quot;Galvanic corrosion is an electrochemical process in which one metal corrodes preferentially to another when both metals are in electrical contact, in the presence of an electrolyte. This same galvanic reaction is exploited in primary batteries to generate an electrical voltage.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don't see any electrolytes in your set-up to generate the required electric voltage. As long as you keep your system free of liquids that could carry such electrolytes, you're fine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T00:51:59.367" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="52" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:02:00.727" Score="3" ViewCount="184" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am looking for multi-position bi-stable solenoids. So far, I have only found one vendor&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; with a 3 position bi-stable solenoid.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there multi-position bi-stable solenoids with more than three positions? How can a 3 position bi-stable solenoid be mechanically amplified to multiple positions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why are these such a rare commodity? What are the alternatives other than stepper motors?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Note, I'm not looking for a vendor recommendation, I'm trying to find out if I'm looking for the right thing. &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="282" LastEditDate="2015-03-04T00:19:10.097" LastActivityDate="2015-03-04T13:09:07.073" Title="Multi-position bi-stable solenoids in a small form factor" Tags="&lt;electrical-engineering&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="53" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="37" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:04:32.327" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;Based on it being an EN steel grade:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first number is 100x the carbon content percentage (so 0.11%), the letters are added elements (sulphur and maganese), and the last number is the sulfur content (0.30%).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.steelnumber.com/en/steel_composition_eu.php?name_id=155&quot;&gt;You can see the full details here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The full format seems to be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[X][% carbon][added elements][% of added elements, hyphenated]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the X is only present for stainless steels.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mobile.euro-inox.org/map/EN_name/EN_en_name.php&quot;&gt;Here is a good example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note also that this scheme is somewhat ambiguous.  The percentages are only an approximation, and the example you gave is interesting because it lists Sulfur before Maganese, despite the naming convention stating that they should be listed in order of content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That's alright for getting quick basic info about the steel, but for anything else you may want to use the EN number, 1.0715, rather than the name.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steel_grades#European_standard_steel_number&quot;&gt;Wikipedia has details on the format&lt;/a&gt;.  Given this classification you can find out much more about the steel's properties and see what general category it fits into.  The site I linked first says this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;EN 10277-3: 2008 Bright steel products&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  Technical delivery conditions. Free-cutting steels  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;EN 10087: 1999 Free cutting steels&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  Technical delivery conditions for semi-finished products, hot rolled bars and rods&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T01:04:32.327" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="54" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="116" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:19:55.740" Score="8" ViewCount="101" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am thinking mainly in $\frac{kWh}{m^3}$ and $\frac{\$}{m^3}$.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past some decades a wide range of surprisingly efficient water desalination plants were built, mainly in desert regions (Middle East). These plants use reverse osmosis via a system of multiple pressered membranes. This solution seems to be very effective in the sense of energy usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it is not enough. Comparing the desalination prices (coming mainly from energy costs) to the alternatives, a further 60-90% reduction is yet needed.  Comparing them, what development potential is there in water desalination?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think water desalination has probably a theoretical energy limit, which could be maybe calculated from entropy and binding energy formulas.  How near are we to this theoretical limit?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-07-21T23:03:43.630" LastActivityDate="2015-07-22T17:07:49.477" Title="What development possibilities could yet exist in water desalination?" Tags="&lt;water-resources&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="55" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="58" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:23:13.033" Score="10" ViewCount="1816" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been investigating recapturing energy from house lighting using solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there solar panels specifically designed to capture indoor lighting with a higher efficiency?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If so, what are the differences between the outdoor and indoor solar panels designed for this purpose?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://solarcellcentral.com/limits_page.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Solar Efficiency Limits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://classroom.synonym.com/can-solar-batteries-charge-using-incandescent-light-7189.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can Solar Batteries Charge Using Incandescent Light?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/Can-solar-panels-charge-from-96493.S.209515615&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can solar panels charge from street lights, during the night? As it does charge from the sun during the day!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="110" LastEditDate="2015-08-22T23:22:38.750" LastActivityDate="2015-09-13T12:24:22.443" Title="Are there different solar panels for recapturing energy from household lighting?" Tags="&lt;electrical-engineering&gt;&lt;photovoltaics&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="56" PostTypeId="5" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:28:43.910" Score="0" Body="" OwnerUserId="-1" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T01:28:43.910" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T01:28:43.910" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="57" PostTypeId="4" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:28:43.910" Score="0" Body="Questions related to Design of Experiments, as a methodological practice. " OwnerUserId="104" LastEditorUserId="160" LastEditDate="2015-01-22T18:50:14.550" LastActivityDate="2015-01-22T18:50:14.550" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="58" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="55" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:42:10.390" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't think they existed, and it has its reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First: a solar panel can be characterized mainly by its efficiency spectrum: on which wavelength, which ratio of light energy can it convert to electric power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This needs to have its maximum around the visible light, becausd the Sun gives most of its energy in this wavelength interval.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is because our eyes can see best in this spectrum. We simply evolved to the sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And this is because home light is also in this wavelength: this is what we, human, like at most.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were no need for different solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But the power of the sunlight is around some hundred $\frac{W}{m^2}$, although it varies very heavily:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.stack.imgur.com/BGrY1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The light power of a house bulb is around sometimes 10W - not for a $m^2$, but for a whole room! Maybe, we see in a well lighted room just so good as in sunlight, but it is only because our eye is very adaptive. The actual light power density is tenth, or even hundredth smaller, as in sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And the efficiency of most solar panels is around 10-20%. There are experimental, very costly version reaching 40%. A solar panel in a room couldn't produce valuable energy, at most some watts - on the cost of the price of a solar panel on the roof. And the cost is their main problem even with their, many, many times bigger solar power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="9" LastEditDate="2015-02-24T04:22:35.200" LastActivityDate="2015-02-24T04:22:35.200" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="59" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="55" CreationDate="2015-01-21T01:46:29.707" Score="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;My gut feel is that you would be able to save more energy than you could re-capture by eliminating light wastage and lowering the energy usage of the light source accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me use a thought experiment to explain:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you were in a white cube-shaped room with a light in the roof and a large window in one wall with black curtains. At night when there's no light from the window if your curtains are open, you lose all that light, if you draw the curtains it's no better as they are black so they absorb it and the room is no lighter. However, if you make the curtains white the room will be a bit brighter and you can lower the power consumption of your light to get the same brightness in the room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, if you put a solar panel all over one of the white walls of your room, you now have something &quot;re-capturing&quot; the energy, but the room is darker because that light is no longer adding to the brightness of the room by being reflected, so you need to increase the energy of your light to get the same brightness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to inefficiencies of energy conversion from electricity to light and in re-capturing that and converting it back to electricity, you will always lose more than the extra you have to put in in order to maintain the same room-brightness. Therefore it's more efficient to lower the light usage and optimise the room for reflecting more of the light back in (white surfaces).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="95" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T01:46:29.707" CommentCount="2" />
  
</posts>